I like the way your mom thinks.
いいな　お前の母さん
Yeah...
だったら俺は…のこと百人分大切にするよ
In that case, I'll value
you as much as 100 friends...
世界が敵になっても俺だけはお前の友達でいる
Even if the whole world becomes
your enemy, I'll always be your friend.
D-Don't say such embarrassing things!
恥ずかしいこと言ってんじゃねえよ
なあ　俺 お前のこと何て呼べばいい
Hey... What should I call you?
俺のことは　…と呼んでくれ
Me?
Call me...
Then I'm Taka.
じゃあ俺は鷹だ
遅いぞ　鷹
You're slow, Taka!
待てよ
Wait up...
A dream?
夢
遅いぞ　鷹
You're slow, Taka!
待てよ
Wait for me...
ダメだ　思い出せない
No good. I can't remember.
WANAWANA
QUIVER
Vigorously bursting with goodness
グッと Good 弾ける
You know, that's surprisingly addicting
案外なんだい ハマってんじゃん
Let's get the ball rolling
while you're idly acting shy!
人見知りしてる暇に 始めよう
Let's make friends and play, yeah!
友達 作っちゃって遊んじゃって Yeah
"Haganai"
クールに見えて 実は超寂しい
I look cool, but I'm actually super lonely
(My delusions went bye, bye, bye
Best friends are a nope, nope, nope, nope)
妄想ならバイバイバイ
親友なら いないいないいないいない
I'm not held back any, but this isn't enough
何不自由なく だけど足りない
(Is a happy life in the real world far, far, far away?
Best friends are a nope, nope, nope, nope)
リア充から遠い遠い遠い
親友なら いないいないいないいない
If a group of unlucky people gathered together,
残念同士で 集まったら
Ah...I can't picture it
Ah- 予想が出来ない 展開の 地雷を踏んだ
This situation is like stepping on a mine!
FIDGET
SOWASOWA
I totally, totally want to take a peek
絶対絶対覗きたい
I don't want to regret this 100 times
後悔100回したくないって
Totally toss aside and
shake off that boring pride
つまんない プライドなんて
捨てきっちゃって 振りきっちゃって
Unfortunately, this idea popped into my mind,
and you know, it's surprisingly addicting
残念観念してみたら
案外なんだいハマってんじゃん
Let's find some as we
clash and rattle each other!
ぶつかって どぎまぎ合って 見つけよう
Let's make friends and play, yeah!
友達 作っちゃって遊んじゃって Yeah
I totally, totally want to take a peek
絶対絶対覗きたい
You! Toss aside and shake yourself off
YOU！ 捨てきっちゃって 振りきっちゃって
Yes! Well? What do you think of that?
Yes！ どーだいどーだいそこんとこ
本字幕由诸神卖萌组(kamigami.org)出品 仅供交流学习之用 禁止用于商业用途
---诸神卖萌组---
日听：apollius   翻译: Justin    校对：喵儿 小草爱吃梨
时间轴：nono   后期：Maize
"Girls are Super Cute in Yukatas"
"Congratulations, Track and Field Club"
"Congratulations, Brass Band Club"
One more week left of summer vacation.
夏休みもあと一週間か
Well, it looks like I'll finish
summer homework during the break...
まあ休み中には宿題終わりそうだな
Come to think of it...
そういえば
There's a summer festival tomorrow
明日は遠夜駅前商店街の神社で夏祭りがある
at the shrine near the Tooya shopping district.
A festival...
祭りか
え  続きは
And?
続き
There's a summer festival, right?
夏祭りがあるんでしょ
Yeah...
ああ 学校に来る途中で提灯がぶら下がっていたのを
I just remembered seeing a hanging
paper lantern on the way to school.
今ふと思い出しただけだ
So you just wanted to say that?
言ってみただけ
みんなでお祭り行ってみようとかじゃないんだ
You weren't gonna suggest we
all go to the festival together...
Why should I bother going to a
place that's probably overcrowded?
どうしてわざわざ人が多そうな場所に行かなければならないのだ
まったくその通りです
Exactly.
A long time ago, Rika tried going to
理科もずっと前に東京で年二回開かれている同人誌のお祭りに行こうとしたのですが
the biannual doujinshi fair in Tokyo...
...but the train on the way was so cramped,
行きの電車があまりにも窮屈だったので
Rika got off en route and went home.
途中で降りて帰っちゃいました
Ever since, Rika's been aware that
festivals are hard for her to deal with.
それ以来お祭りには苦手意識があります
I've heard of that fair before.
聞いたことあるな  その祭り
It's supposed to be really crowded
たしか あそこでしか買えない本もあるから
because that's the only place
you can buy certain books, right?
あんなに人が集まるんだろ
You weren't interested enough to get them?
お前はそういうのは手に入れなくていいのか
おっと なかなか痛いところを突いてきますね先輩
Oh, you just struck a nerve, Sempai.
Striking a girl and causing her
pain isn't an admirable thing to do.
女の子を突いて痛がらせるのは感心しませんよ
Don't drag the conversation
down to the gutter level!
強引に下ネタに持っていくんじゃねえ
If you strip the gutter level
away from Rika, what's left?!
理科から下ネタを取ったらいったい何が残るというのですか
How about a brilliant inventor or a scientist...
天才発明家とか科学者とか
...or a cool character with
glasses? There's plenty!
クールキャラとか眼鏡とかあるだろ
もっと自分を信じろよ
Have more faith in yourself.
それらはすべてギャップによって下ネタを引き立てるための道具に過ぎません
All of those things are mere
tools to highlight indecent topics,
because of their incongruity.
Smut is Rika's true nature!
下ネタこそが理科の本質です
Incidentally, those
books that aren't distributed
ちなみに 流通しないような本は
企業で参加しているゲーム会社の人に頼んで手に入れてもらったりしています
are obtained for Rika
through people who work for
video game companies she's assisted on projects.
It wouldn't be an overstatement to say
理科はこのためにゲーム会社のお手伝いをしていると言っても過言ではありません
that this is the reason Rika
helps these game companies!
Huh... You've really thought of lots
of ways to make up for being a shut-in.
へえ 引きこもりをカバーするために色々考えてるんだな
えへん
See?
ね ねえ小鷹
H-Hey, Kodaka...
At summer festivals, do they, uh...
夏祭りっていうのにはその
D-Do they have octopus dumpling stalls?
た たこ焼きの屋台も出るのかしら
屋台が出るなら確実にあるんじゃないか
Well, they must have food stalls, anyway...
You like octopus dumplings?
お前 たこ焼き好きなのか
わ 悪い
S-Something wrong with that?
No, I love 'em.
いや 俺も大好きだぞ
A long time ago, when I lived in Osaka,
昔大阪住んでて
周りの人とノリが合わなくてふさぎがちになって
I didn't fit in at all with the people
around me, and was kind of depressed...
But the octopus dumplings my dad brought home
父さんが買ってきてくれる名店のたこ焼きだけを
from a well-known store became my comfort food.
心の支えにして生きてたこともあったくらいだ
Delicious octopus dumplings can save the mind.
おいしいたこ焼きは人の心を救ってくれる
On the other hand...
逆に
俺 まずいたこ焼きを平気な顔して売ってる連中は許せないな
...I can't tolerate bastards who sell crappy
octopus dumplings with a straight face!
W-Wait, Kodaka!
ま 待ってよ 小鷹
I'm not that into octopus dumplings!
あたしはそこまでたこ焼きにヘビーな思い入れはないわよ
I just like them because they taste good...
普通においしいから 好きっていうだけで
クックックッ　久しぶりに我にたこ焼きを供することを許すぞ
It's been a long time, so I would
accept octopus dumplings as an offering.
You wanna eat octopus dumplings too, Kobato?
小鳩も　たこ焼き食いたいのか
Octopus dumplings!
たこ焼き
あッ　お兄ちゃん
Big Brother! I wanna eat octopus dumplings, too!
私もたこ焼き食べたいです
Mmm, then why don't we go together
to the summer festival tomorrow?
それじゃ一緒に行くか
明日の夏祭り
行く
Let's go!
Why do you have to go?! Odious agent of God!
なぜ　貴様まで一緒に行くのだ
忌まわしき神の手先よ
I wanna go alone with Big Brother!
私はお兄ちゃんと２人で行きたいのだ
- You go home, poopy vampire!
- Me too! Me too! I'm going, too!
お前は帰れ　うんこ吸血鬼
はいはい　あたしも行くわよ たこ焼き食べたいから
I wanna eat octopus dumplings!
兄貴　私もご一緒したいです
Aniki, I want to join as well.
Sure.
分かった
じゃあ 星奈と幸村を入れて５人で行くか
So, with Sena and Yukimura,
that makes five of us who're going...
- W-Wait, Kodaka!
- Wait a moment, Sempai!
待つのだ小鷹　私も行くぞ
待ってください　理科も行きます
- I'm going to the summer festival, too!
- Rika's going to the summer festival, too!
Why, again?
何でまた
I thought you two weren't good with crowds...
お前ら人ごみ苦手なんじゃ
たこ焼きのためです
たこ焼きのためだ
For the octopus dumplings!
I see! You're willing to brave the crowd
for the sake of the octopus dumplings, huh?
そうか　たこ焼きのためなら仕方ないな
I understand!
Kodaka-sempai!
小鷹せんぱ～い
Hi! Everyone's early!
よう　みんな早いな
あッ　理科
R-Rika...
Look what you can do
when you put your mind to it!
お前　やればできるじゃないか
What's that, a backhanded compliment?!
何ですか　その微妙な言い方は
Please compliment me more directly!
もっと素直に褒めてくださいよ
That looks great on you.
メチャクチャ似合ってる
I-It's embarrassing when you're that direct!
そんなにストレートに言われたらテレるじゃないですか
Silly Sempai.
先輩のバカ
What do you want me to do?
どうしろってんだよ
Now only Meat isn't here.
あと来ていないのは肉だけか
So let's go.
だったら　もう出発しよう
What do you mean "let's go," stupid Yozora?
何で「だったら」なのよ バカ夜空
Jeez. A girl can't be too careful around you.
全く油断も隙もないわね　あんた
この私が来ないと
Anyway, nothing can start without me, right?
何も始まらないでしょう
What was that for?!
何すんだよ
何でもない　さっさと行くぞ
Nothing. Now let's go!
Hey, wait!
おい　待てよ
"Tooya Station Square Shopping District"
小鷹 どういうことよ
Kodaka, what's the meaning of this?
It's a summer festival and you didn't have
Kobato-chan wear a yukata? Is that a joke?
なんでせっかくの夏祭りなのに
小鳩ちゃんが浴衣じゃないのよふざけてんの
べつに祭りだからって みんなが浴衣着てるわけじゃないだろ
It's not like everyone
wears a yukata to a festival.
You don't need to bring the common folk into it!
一般大衆のことなんていいのよ
あたしが小鳩ちゃんの浴衣姿を見たいのよ
I want to see Kobato-chan in a yukata!
Neither Kobato nor I have a yukata, anyway...
俺も小鳩も浴衣持ってないしな
Sempai!
先輩　そこの呉服店で浴衣のレンタルやってるみたいですよ
It looks like you can rent
yukatas from that kimono shop!
"We have yukatas for rent."
Let's go!
すぐ行くわよ
You wanna wear a cute yukata
too, don't you, Kobato-chan?
小鳩ちゃんもかわいい浴衣着たいわよね
Mmm...
What do you say we try on a
yukata, as long as we're here?
せっかくだから浴衣着てみるか
- Okay...
- I wanna get to the octopus dumplings!
私は早くたこ焼きが食べたいぞ
クックックッ　貴様はここで悠久の時をすごすがいい
You should spend eternity here...
何を　吸血鬼のクセに
What?! A vampire talks to me like that?!
うん　そうだな
Yeah...
Yukimura, why don't you go on ahead
and buy some octopus dumplings?
幸村　先行ってたこ焼きとか適当に買ってやってくれるか
Understood. I'm pleased to be your gofer, Aniki.
分かりました　喜んで兄貴のパシリをさせていただきます
You come, too.
ほら　あんたも行くわよ
I don't need a yukata.
私は浴衣などいらん
Your looks are the only decent thing about you,
あんた見た目だけはそこそこまともなんだし
so it'd be a waste if you don't wear a yukata.
浴衣着ないともったいないじゃない
Yeah, now that you mention it, a yukata
ああ確かに　夜空の長い黒髪は浴衣に映えるんじゃないか
would probably accent Yozora's long, black hair.
N-No...
I don't like that kind of style.
私はそういう格好は好かん
"Tooya Summer Festival"
Too bad, I bet she'd look good in a yukata...
浴衣　似合いそうなのにな
Bro!
あんちゃん
かわいい かわいい かわいすぎて食べちゃいたいくらい
Cute! Cute! Cute!
どう
- You're so cute I wanna eat you up!
- Well?
似合ってるぞ
It looks pretty damn good...
You remind me of a stupid "new adult"
I saw on the news, who was arrested
そういうあんたは前にニュースで見たどっかの成人式で
暴れて逮捕されたバカな新成人みたいね
at a coming-of-age ceremony
for disorderly conduct.
But I liked it...
自分では気に入ってたのに
But I guess the real problem
is your pudding-colored hair.
ていうか　やっぱりさ
あんたの失敗したプリンみたいな髪の毛が問題なのよ
My hair?
髪
I think that hair is the main reason you're
taken for a juvenile delinquent at school.
学校で不良だと思われているのもその頭が一番の原因なんじゃない
Why don't you dye it black?
どうして黒に染めないの
I have seriously thought
about dyeing it before...
染めようと本気で考えたこともあるんだけどな
...but you know that my mom isn't alive, right?
俺の母さんがもういないってことは知ってるよな
Mm... Yeah...
うん　まあ
俺　顔は父親似であんまりハーフっぽくないだろ
My face looks like my dad's, so it's
hard to tell I'm only half-Japanese, right?
I wish I was like Kobato, who
has both our mom's face and hair...
母親似のこいつみたいに
顔だちから金髪までソックリだとよかったんだけどな
"Yukata Sale"
But this hair is the only thing
I've inherited from my mom
なんで　この髪の毛が
母親から受け継いだ見た目で分かる唯一のものなんだ
that you can tell by looking at me.
It feels like dyeing it would
be denying my connection to her.
それを染めるってことは母さんとのつながりを否定する気がするんだ
Even if it's the reason
for some bad experiences...
たとえ　このせいでイヤな思いをすることがあってもな
Kodaka...
小鷹　あんたやっぱり他の男子とは違うわね
You really are different
from other boys, aren't you?
Come on, let's go!
さあ　行くわよ
Should we go?
行くか
Yeah!
"Offering"
Oh, there they are!
Sorry to keep you guys waiting!
お待たせ
おかひぇり　おぶぃひゃん
Welgum bah!
Don't talk with your mouth full.
飲み込んでからしゃべれ
お好み焼きもうまいのだ
The okonomiyaki are good, too!
How the hell much can you eat?
どんだけ食うんだ　貴様は
Is this Heaven?!
もしかして　ここは天国なのか
What kind of way to eat is that?
何なんだ　その食べ方は
I'm practicing erotic
eating on a chocolate banana.
チョコバナナをいやらしく食べる練習です
Does it excite you?
興奮しますか
しねえよ
Not at all.
Here, Kobato-chan.
はい　小鳩ちゃん　あ～ん
イヤッ
No!
う～ん　イマイチ
Mmm... It's missing something...
Aniki...
兄貴 お待たせしました
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Oh, thanks.
おッ　すまんな
Please.
どうぞ
Thank you.
ありがとう
Let's see... I wonder how this one will taste...
どれどれ　次はどうかな
How is it, Aniki?
いかがですか　兄貴
It has kind of a light and fluffy texture,
ふっくら感は多少あるが皮が弱いからすぐ崩れる
but the thin skin makes it fall apart.
"Octopus Dumplings"
And the piece of octopus
inside is too small! This won't do.
そして中のタコが小さい　ありえん
I see...
そうですか
よ～し　みんなでもっとおいしいたこ焼きを探しに行くぞ
All right! Let's all look for a
better octopus dumpling stand!
I've had enough to eat.
もう食べ物はいい
Rika, too.
理科もです
Big Brother, I wanna eat that
thing that looks like a cloud next!
お兄ちゃん　私は次は雲みたいなのが食べたいぞ
クックックッ 今宵の供物は豪勢であった
This evening's offerings were grand!
I'm stuffed.
もう　おなかいっぱい
But...
そんな
Sena! Everyone! Didn't you wanna
eat delicious octopus dumplings?!
星奈　みんなもおいしいたこ焼きを食べたいんじゃなかったのか
Eh, whatever.
もう　どうでもいいわ
- What did we come to this festival for?!
- Well, I think everyone's full, so...
さて　おなかもふくれたことだし
Shall we go home?
帰るか
We might as well go home...
帰りましょうか
えッ　帰っちゃうの
You're going home?!
たこ焼きも食べたことだし もうここに用はないだろう
We ate octopus dumplings,
so what else would we do here?
俺は満足してないぞ
I'm not satisfied!
Th-That's right! And as long as
we're here, we can play games...
そうよ　せっかくだから ついでに遊んでいっても
いい年をして金魚すくいだの 輪投げだのやりたいのか
At your age, you want to scoop
for goldfish and throw rings?
べ べつに　そういうわけじゃないけど
N-No, it's not like that...
ていうか あんたこそ私にお祭りの遊びで負けるのが怖いから
I mean, don't tell me you
wanna go home right away
because you're scared I'll beat
you at the festival's games?!
さっさと帰ろうとしてるんじゃないでしょうね
I told you from the
beginning that I hate crowds.
私は人ごみが嫌いだと最初から言ってるだろうが
You have a short memory, Meat.
物覚えの悪い肉だな
Although... this looks like nothing
compared to the pool the other day...
だが　まあ先日のプールに比べたら全然マシなようだ
I think I'll acquaint you
with reality, cheeky Meat.
生意気な肉に現実を分からせてやるか
フッ　それじゃあいくわよ
Then let's go.
First, let's see, I wanna
try that goldfish scooping...
まずはそうね
金魚すくいっていうのがやってみた
I-I mean... I challenge you to
a goldfish scooping showdown!
違う 金魚すくいで勝負してあげるわ
フンッ　神がすくいにきてあげたわよ　金魚ども
Hmph. Your goddess has
come to save you, goldfish.
I'm going to shatter your idiotic delusion.
貴様のくだらん妄想を打ち砕いてやろう
I am the goddess here.
私こそが神だ
Here you are, Sir!
はい　おじさん
Yep.
ほい　はいよ
There ya go!
Thank you!
ありがとう
Go!
何よこれ　破れるじゃない
What is this?! It ripped!
That's because it's paper.
そりゃ紙だからな
The idea is to catch a
goldfish without letting it rip.
破らずに金魚をすくわないと
ああ　もうおとなしく私にすくわれなさいよクソ金魚
Oh, come on! Just stay still and
let me catch you, damn goldfish!
仕入れ値　数円程度の分際でこの私に散財させるとは
How dare you make me
throw my money away on you
when you cost only a handful of yen?!
I'll take ten of them together!
１０枚まとめてちょうだい
Sure...
はいよ
I did it!
やった
Wha?! That's not fair!
貴様　ずるいぞ
これが戦略ってやつよ
It's called "strategy"!
Please don't cheat like that...
そういうズルはやめてほしいんだけどね
"Goldfish Scooping"
I'll look the other way if you take a hike.
見逃してやるから もうあっち行ってくんねえかな
Be thankful, fishy!
感謝しなさいよね　あんた
From now on, your name is "Kandata."
これから　あんたの名前はカンダタよ　ありがたく思いなさい
Be grateful!
肉　次はあれにするぞ
Meat!
We'll do that next!
"Candy Diecutting"
"100 yen each time"
No matter what we do, it's a
foregone conclusion that I'll win!
何をやっても 私が勝つに決まってるんだから
That last one was through cheating!
さっきのはズルだろうが 行くぞ
Let's go!
You're on!
受けて立とうじゃない
先輩　あの２人はほっといて
- Sempai, why don't we leave those
two alone and play with each other?
- Hey, Meat! That's too simple!
理科達も遊びませんか
それは簡単すぎるたろう
そうだな
Yeah...
- Yay!
- I'm gonna play with Big Brother!
やった お兄ちゃんと遊ぶのだ
クックックッ 我の水風船の方が大きい
My water balloon is bigger than yours!
- Mine is prettier, so I win, dummy!
- You!
私のやつの方がキレイなので
私の勝ちなのだ　バーカバーカ
あんたね あれで勝ったとか本気で言ってるわけ
Do you seriously think you won with that?!
誰がどう見ても私の勝利だろうが
Anybody could see it was my victory!
You couldn't even carve
an umbrella! Pathetic, Meat!
傘も抜けなかったくせに
見苦しいぞ　肉
私は　あんなチマチマしたもの合わないのよ
I'm not cut out for that
kind of puny detail work!
あッ　あっち
There!
"Roulette" "The Best: 100!"
"Sauce Rice Crackers, 200 Yen a Spin"
Let's have a showdown with that roulette wheel!
あのルーレットで勝負よ
Sauce rice crackers...
ソースせんべいか　いいだろう
Fine!
How was that?
どうですか
I don't believe it...
そんなバカな
Here. The special prize!
えいッ　特賞
Sempai! Rika already has this
game system, so she's giving it to you.
先輩　理科はこのゲーム機持ってるんで先輩にあげます
Please think of it as Rika and play with it!
これを理科だと思ってもてあそんでください
Then, let's put it in the club room.
じゃあ 部室の備品にしようぜ
えッ　そうですね
G-Good idea...
Meat! That was lowdown, Meat!
肉　汚いぞ　肉
Shut up, stupid Yozora!
うるさい　バカ夜空
"Sauce Rice Crackers"
私の勝利は勝利でしょうが
My win was a win!
That's no kind of win!
そんなの絶対に認めん
You two get the hell outta here!
あんたら　あっちへ行ってくれ
Here.
ほら
Thank you, Sempai!
ありがとうございます　先輩
Kodaka, I've been looking for you!
小鷹　捜したわよ
I figured you could hold my stuff!
荷物持ってもらおうと思ったのに
All these prizes are getting
in the way of our showdown.
景品が邪魔で勝負が続けられない
Help us carry them, Kodaka!
運ぶの手伝え　小鷹
I can't! I've already got stuff to carry.
無理無理　見りゃ分かるだろ
A-A game system?!
ゲ ゲーム機だと
How?!
何で
It's thanks to "Deadeye Rika."
撃墜王　理科と呼んでください
I guess that does it for tonight...
今日はここまでね
Well, I'm sure if we
kept going, I would've won...
まあ　このまま続けていたら私が勝っていただろうがな
What are you talking about?!
何言ってんのよ　私の方が１勝リードしてるでしょうが
I'm ahead by one win!
The goldfish scoop doesn't count, idiot...
金魚すくいはノーカウントだ　バカ
おい　幸村達と合流するぞ
Hey, let's meet up with Yukimura and the girls.
Yeah. I'll be waiting at
the west gate of the shrine.
うん　神社の西門で待ってるから
Stella-san said she'll pick you up?
ステラさん来てくれるって
Yeah, but because of the festival, she said
うん でも今日は祭りだから車だと時間が読めないって
she doesn't know how long
it'll take to get here by car.
I see...
そっか
Hey, since we're here, how
about shooting off fireworks?
なあ せっかくだから花火やらないか
We have a lot of them...
たくさんあるし
Fireworks!
花火
I agree. After all, I doubt we'll have
賛成だ
この先 花火をやる機会もなさそうだし
another chance to do fireworks after this.
I've only ever done fireworks in games before!
花火なんてゲームのイベントでしかやったことないわね
It sounds like fun!
楽しそう
Then I'll buy a bucket and some candles!
じゃあ バケツと蝋燭買ってくる
I'm gonna light it.
つけるぞ
It's on fire! It's totally on fire!
燃えとる　メッチャ燃えとるげ
クックックッ　見るがいい
Gaze upon my secret fire magic technique!
これが我が魔炎術の秘奥義
煉獄の炎に焼かれて朽ち果てるがいい　メギドフレイム
Burn in the fire of
purgatory and die in obscurity!
Megiddo Flame!
私もやるぞ
I'm doing it, too!
Don't copy me, idiot!
マネするなアホ
Rika will investigate fireworks next.
理科　今度花火を研究してみることにします
People's dreams are fleeting...
人の夢と書いて「儚い」
I guess a person's life is like a sparkler,
人の生もまた瞬いて消える 花火のごとしなのでしょう
lasting but an instant before dying out.
トリプル花火
Triple sparklers!
You've got a long way to go!
その程度じゃまだまだね
Finally the last boss, huh?
ついにラスボスか
This is the last one.
これが最後ですね
That's it?
終わり
Disappointing, just like Meat.
まるで　肉のような残念さだな
どういう意味よ　それ
What's that supposed to mean?!
Just when I'm disappointed,
you pull it off, Last Boss!
残念かと思ったらやるじゃないかラスボスめ
フフッ　そうでしょ
Yeah, right?
It wasn't meant as a compliment to you, Meat!
お前を褒めたわけじゃないぞ　肉
It's still going! Guess it's
not the final boss for nothing!
まだあるとはさすがラスボスですね
Huh? Does something stink?
あれッ　何か臭くないか
That isn't the smell of gunpowder...
これ 火薬のにおいじゃないですね
あッ　夜空　燃えてるわよ
Hey, Y-Yozora!
You're on fire, Yozora!
あんた　夜空
W-Water!
水
- There!
- Turn around, Yozora!
後ろ向け　夜空
R-Right!
The fire is out...
火は消えてます
あの　夜空
Um... Yozora...
I'm going home.
帰る
Yozora...
夜空
In the one week between then
and the end of summer vacation...
それから 夏休みが終わるまでの一週間
...we didn't see Yozora at Neighbors Club.
夜空は隣人部に姿を見せなかった
"September 1"
Tanabe.
田辺
はい
Here!
Tsuda.
津田
はい
Here...
Hasegawa.
羽瀬川
Yeah...
はい
Hirasawa.
平沢
Here!
はい
Fujioka.
藤岡
Here.
はい
Horiguchi.
鳥口
Here.
はい
- Matsushita.
- Yozora...
夜空
Here.
Mikazuki.
三日月
Here!
はい
Well, I'll call it "safe."
Hurry up and take your seat.
まあ　セーフにしておく 早く席に着きなさい
Yes, Sir.
はい
...Sora?
ソラ
Long time no see, Taka.
久しぶり　鷹
That was...
それは １０年ぶりの久しぶりだった
...a ten-year "long time no see."
Ah, my mind is escaping
reality as ideally as imaginable
あー 脳內 想像理想の 現実逃避
Not that it really matters
now if I... make friends
今更どっちだっていっけど 友達作り
Those eyes that belittle me saying,
"You're a lonesome person on your own," bug me
一人寂しい奴だと蔑む 視線が気になる
So, while I was thinking that it'd be cool...
で 上っ面だけ集まったら
それでいいと 思っているうちに
...if only a superficial group gathered up,
They show up, one here,
one there, and gather together
あれよあれよと登場 揃って 破天荒な奴らに
The unique characters
Throw me off balance
マイペース 乱されてゆく 頭くる！特に憎っくき肉
It ticks me off! Especially that mean meat!
My chest is secretly filled with
apprehension and I feel a bit indecisive
私の胸秘かに焦って 優柔不斷気味で
I can't tell you what's in my heart
My heart 伝えられない 殘念なのは 私なのか
Am I the one disappointed by that?
Plow through the fog today!
もやもやを かきわけ Today！
Ever since the day I got left behind,
my maiden heart has been filled with regret
置き去りにされた 乙女心 あの日から悔やんでいる
Hurry and find it...my lost heart
早く見つけ出して 迷子のココロ
So after the summer festival,
Yozora didn't come to the Neighbors Club.
結局　夏祭りのあとの隣人部はずっと夜空がいない状態だった
Ahhh, the club room is so refreshing
without that stupid vixen around!
いや　あのバカギツネがいない部室はホントすがすがしいわ
Hey, that's not a nice thing to say!
それは　ちょっとヒドくないか
事実は事実でしょ
The truth is the truth!
あ　私は困るのだ
It's a problem for me!
I need Yozora here!
夜空がいないと絶対絶対困るのだ
Why? What's wrong?!
何だ　どうした
If Yozora doesn't come,
I don't get my potato chips!
夜空が来ないとポテチがもらえないのだ
That's why?
そこかよ
Next time: "We Don't Have Many Friends."
"Next time: We Don't Have Many Friends"
次回　「僕達は友達が少ない」
Well, I guess it's so relaxing
without her here, there's nothing to do...
あいつがいないとせいせいすぎてヒマかもね